<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post #2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2024/09/15/blog-post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2024/09/15/blog-post-2/</guid>
      <description>Voters &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;The Economy&amp;rdquo; Gross Domestic Product (GDP) Unemployment Consumer Price Index (CPI) Models in Review Prediction, and a Note on Incumbency </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post #1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2024/09/08/blog-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2024/09/08/blog-post-1/</guid>
      <description>Competitiveness on the National Stage As we enter the final, frantic months of the 2024 presidential election with the two major party candidates, former President Donald Trump and Vice President Kamala Harris, “effectively tied” according to Reuters’ analysis of a recent NY Times/Siena poll, circumstances beg the question: how competitive are American presidential elections, anyway? Put another way, if current national polls end up being a fair predictor of the vote share margin come Election Day, will this razor-tight race be out of step with historical elections?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/post/2024/09/03/assignment-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/post/2024/09/03/assignment-0/</guid>
      <description>Overview: In this assignment, we will work with historical national popular vote and state-level popular vote data from presidential elections. We will restructure the two data sets and eventually merge them, before running basic linear models to predict the national popular vote from the vote in certain states.&#xA;Data Details:&#xA;File Name: state_2pv_1948_2020.csv&#xA;These data contain the state-level popular vote from presidential elections from 1948 through 2020.&#xA;Variable Name Variable Description year election year state state candidate candidate party candidate&amp;rsquo;s party candidatevotes votes received by the candidate in the state totalvotes total votes cast in the state vote_share proportion of total votes received by the candidate two_party_votes total votes cast for Republicans and Democrats in the state two_party_vote_share proportion of Democratic and Republican votes received by the candidate File Name: nat_pv_1860_2020.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
